## TIANYIN ZHANG

San Jose, CA 95148 | tianyinzhang.com | (408)609-4697 | tianyinzhang1999@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

A creative and forward-thinking Computer Science major who enjoys web development as well as learning new technology. Experienced software developer, team contributor, and analytical problem-solver with strong learning capability and communication skills. Specifically aims to solve ambiguous problems with practical solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming Language: JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Tools: Figma, Photoshop, MongoDB, Firebase, ExpressJS, ReactJS, TailwindCSS, NodeJS, Bootstrap, Git/Github, CommandLine.
- Agile Methodology, Scrum Framework.
- Time and Tasks Management, Organization and Coordination, Collaborative working.
- Hobbies: Personal Electric Vehicle, Photography, Videography.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Founder, PEV NYC, New York, NY

October 2021 - Present

- Founded, supervised, and grow a local non-profit PEV hobbyist group with healthy growth.
- Attracted more than 150 active members within first year.
- Hosting, and supervising weekly in-person events, online discussion space.
- Engage sponsors and coordinate events for relative businesses in the industry: local small businesses, and international manufacturers.

# Full Stack Developer, MERN Mobile Web App (Course Project), New York, NY

January 2023 - May 2023

- Developed and deployed a mobile-focused web app using ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, and MongoDB.
- Led development process under the Agile methodology and Scrum Framework.
- Partnered with 4 other teammates with designing, coding, troubleshooting, debugging, and deployment.
- Implemented optimized code base for high efficiency in using the app.

### Full Stack Developer, JavaScript Web App (Course Project), New York, NY

September 2022 - December 2022

- Developed a multi-page web app uses JavaScript, React.JS, Firebase (database, Auth, Hosting), HTML, and CSS.
- Managed both back-end and front-end aspects of development process.
- Led sessions for code review, version-control duties, debug, and refactor code base.
- Collaborated with 3 teammates under agile methodology and Scrum Framework, served team as Scrum Master.

### Founder, Discord Gaming Community, San Jose, CA

March 2018 - December 2019

- Created one of the biggest student-focused online gaming communities.
- Attracted 30,000 total members within first 1.5 years.
- Managed a team of moderators to maintain a healthy community environment.
- Hosted various online events such as tournaments, talent shows, etc.

#### **EDUCATION**

## New York University, College of Arts & Science, New York, NY

September 2019 - May 2023

BA in Computer Science

- Computer Science with a focus on JavaScript and related tech stack.
- Courses taken: Data Structures, Web Dev & Programming, Basic Algorithm, Computer System Organization, Operating Systems, Applied Internet Technology, Remote Collaborating, Agile Software Development & DevOps, Data Management and Analysis.